Let's start with the first step which is to change the price header to say order
我們從第一步開始 這一步是變更
summary.
訂單摘要的價格標題
First I open up the activity_main layout file, and then I go and
首先我打開activity_main版面文件 然后我找到
find the view that controls the price header.
控制價格標題的檢視圖
And I put my cursor here,
把光標放在這里
then I see that this view gets correctly highlighted.
我看到這個檢視圖 正確地高亮顯示
So now I can go ahead and modify this string here.
現在我可以進行操作 修改這里的字串
I'm going to erase this and type in Order Summary.
我要刪除這個 然后鍵入訂單摘要.
It correctly updates in the preview window.
在預覽視窗中 它正確地更新了
Notice that I spelled it with a capital O and
請注意到 我拼寫為 大寫字母O
a capital S instead of in all caps.
和大寫字母S 而不是全部都是大寫
If we ever decide to change our UI and
如果我們決定變更我們的UI
set all caps to be false, then my text will still be fine.
并且全部設定為大寫 我的文字仍然不會出錯
So I prefer typing Order Summary like this and
因此我寫成 像這樣的Order Summary
then using the attribute textAllCaps = true.
然后使用 屬性陳述式textAllCaps = true
Okay, so the first item's done.
好了每一個任務完成了
The second task is to find the price value TextView and
第二個任務是找到 價格值TextView
change it to have an ID of this.
并進行更改 使它具有一個ID
If I move down to the next TextView after the order summary header
如果我移到訂單摘要標題之后的 下一個TextView
then this is the price value TextView, and it's highlighted here too.
這是價格值TextView, 在這里它也高亮顯示
As requested, I'm going to change the ID to say order_summary_text_view.
根據需要 我要把這個ID 變更為order_summary_text_view
Cool, so those are all the XML changes in the layout.
很好 這些都是 版面XML變更
Let me run the app to make sure that it still works.
讓我們來執行應用程式 確保它仍然能夠正常運行
Actually, it doesn't work.
實際上 程式沒有運行
I get an error saying that it can't find the symbol price_text_view
我看到一個錯誤 提示說 它不能在java文件中
in the Java file.
找到符號price_text_view
Looks like we need to go to the next steps before we can get
看來 在編譯我們的應用程之前 我們還需要
our app to compile.
做另外一些事情
In the Main Activity display message method, we are supposed to
在主活動顯示方法中 我們應該
change the variable name from priceTextView to orderSummaryTextView.
把變數名稱priceTextView 更改為orderSummaryTextView
Within the main activity file in the display message method,
在主活動文件內的 顯示訊息方法中
I find the priceTextView here.
我在這里找到priceTextView
I'm going to delete this and then type in orderSummaryTextView.
我需要刪除它 然后鍵入orderSummaryTextView
It's going to be in camelCase and
它將位于camelCase中
start with a lower case o because it's a variable name.
以小寫字母o開頭 因為它是一個變數名稱
Immediately I get a warning that says the variable is never used.
接下來我看到一個報警 說變數從未被使用
So I'm going to copy it, and I'm actually going to use it on the next
因此我要復制它 我要在下一行使用它
line here because there's an error saying priceTextView is unresolved.
因為有一個錯誤說 priceTextView未解析
And then delete this, and then use the new variable name here.
然后刪除這個 然后在這里使用新的變數名稱
Cool, and that makes the error go away.
很好 錯誤不見了
But I still have another error here, and I think it's related to the last task.
但是這里有另外一個錯誤 我認為這與最后一個任務有關
The last item here says to change R.id.price_text_view to
最后一個 任務是把R.id.price_text_view
R.id.order_summary_text_view.
變為R.id.order_summary_text_view
I'm going to double click on this error in red, and
我要雙擊一個這個 顯示為紅色的錯誤
I'm going to delete it and type in order_summary_text_view.
然后我要刪除它 鍵入order_summary_text_view
There, and now the error goes away.
現在錯誤不見了
And now the app works without any errors.
現在應用程式正常運行 而沒有任何錯誤
The initial layout is correct.
初始版面是正確的
Instead of saying price, it now says order summary, and
它不是顯示價格 現在它顯示訂單摘要
if I change the quantity and hit order, then the summary shows up here.
如果我變更數量 然后按一下訂單 這里顯示訂單摘要
Let's talk about any observations that you may have made.
我們來討論 你在這里所看到的內容
Remember there's no right or wrong answers.
記住 沒有正確 或錯誤的答案
First you may have noticed that for the price TextView, when we gave it an ID of
首先你注意到 對于價格TextView 當我們為它提供
order_summary_text_view, the similar format appeared again later in
一個order_summary_text_view ID時 在我們修改displayMessage方法時
the Java code when we were modifying the displayMessage method.
Java代碼中將會再次 相同的格式
You also may have noticed that by changing price to order summary
你還可能注意到 把價格變更為訂單摘要
it seemed to have a bunch of ripple affects on other parts of the code.
看起來對代碼的其他部分 產生了鏈鎖反應
Now some of these changes are required in order for the app to run again, but
現在為了使應用程式再次運行 需要進行一些變更
other changes were more nice to have just for
但是其他變更是為了 遵守規定
convention so that we didn't have any old, lingering references to price.
以避免任何過時 和延續性地引用價格
In looking more closely at the displayMessage method,
我們更仔細地 看displayMessage方法
you may have noticed that there's only one input parameter, string message.
你可能注意到只有一個 輸入參數 字串訊息
And there's no return value.
而且沒有返回值
&gt;&gt; That's why we don't have a line in this method that says return something.
&gt;&gt; 這個方法中沒有代碼行 定義返回值
You also may recognize the word TextView which we saw in the XML in order to add
你還會發現TextView關鍵字 我們在XML中看到過它
a text view to our layout.
其作用是為我們的版面增加一個文字檢視圖
It's spelled exactly the same way as here.
它的拼寫 與這里完全相同
Also, this line of code here looks like the assignment of a variable,
另外 這行代碼看上去 是分配一個變數
where we have the variable data type,
我們設定了變數資料型別
the variable name, and then, having an initial value here.
變數名稱 然后在這里設定初始值
This is similar to how we declare integers and strings.
這與字符串 和整數的宣告方法相似
And if you were looking really closely you may have thought that this looks
如果你更認真地看 你可能會認為 這看上去
like a method call, findViewById followed by an opening parentheses,
像是方法調用 findViewById后面是一個開始括弧
some stuff in the middle, and then a closing parentheses.
里面有內容 然后是一個結束括弧
Similarly with setText here, there's an opening parenthesis,
與這里的setText相似 這里有一個開始括弧
something in the middle, and then a closing parenthesis.
里面有內容 然后是一個結束括弧
So this may also be a method call.
因此這也可能是一個方法調用
In the upcoming videos, we're going to take a look more closely
在接下來的視訊中 我們將會更詳細地討論
at what exactly is happening in these lines of code and
這些代碼行 的作用是什么
start to understand what they actually mean.
然后理解 它們的實際含義